A Finding Aid to the Sherman E. Lee Papers, 1947-1997, in the Archives of American Art aaa.leeshere
Archives of American Art
- Writing Project Files, 1958-1997; Series 4; 1 Linear feet Boxes 4-5
  - Remarks, Cleveland Museum of Art Exhibition, Japanese Folk Art, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - "Chinese Painting," Savannah, Georgia, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - "Chinese Contribution to World Art," Toledo Museum of Art, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Art Museums and the Problems Representative of China: Form and Contents," University of Chicago, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Introduction, Genius of Japanese Design, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "The Nature and the Significance of teh Collection of Liang Ch'ing-Piao," Taiwan Symposium, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "The Importance of Chinese Art," Cummer Gallery of Art, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "Themes and Variations: the Art of Tz'u-Chon Tradition," Indianapolis Museum of Art, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Lecture, Chinese Painting, Kansas City, Missouri, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "The Glories of Bronze Age China," New York Times, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "The Importance of Chinese Art," Atlanta Historical Society, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "5,000 Years of Korean Art," Korean Quarterly Journal, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Address, University of Notre Dame, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Collecting and the Seven Deadly Sins," Friends of the Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "Sins and Virtues of Collecting," Kimball Art Museum, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "Collecting," Philbrook Art Center, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Lecture, San Antonio Art Museum, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "Water, Trees and Rocks: Chinese Painting 1350-1650," Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller III Collection," Conaissance Des Aets, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Remarks, Art Dealers Association of American Awards, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - "The Sins and Virtues of Collecting," Center for Fine Arts, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "Reflections of Reality in Japanese Art," Connaissance des Arts, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Article, Museum Education, International Encyclopedia of Education, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - on Richard Fuller, Seattle Art Museum, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - "The View from the Japanese Landscape Print," Junior Council
  - "Bits and Pieces from the Past," Intown Club, Cleveland, Ohio, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - "Asian Art and Culture," Smithsonian Institution, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Travel Files, 1959-1997; Series 5; 1.8 Linear feet Boxes 5-7
  Travel files contain itineraries; travel diaries; research material including photographs of works of art; travel documents including passports, plane tickets, and reservations; photographs of groups of delegations; lists of participants; correspondence; and reports. Of note are the travel diaries which may include traditional diary entries, contact addresses, and notes. Files are found for Lee's travel for the Cleveland Museum of Art and for independent trips, likely for his consulting work.
  Material is organized chronologically. The series is arranged as 2 subseries.
  5.1: Cleveland Museum of Art, 1959-1983
  5.2: General, 1988-1994
  - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1959-1983; 5.1
    - Trip Itineraries, 1959-1983 (Box 5, Folder 26-28)
    - Europe, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 29-30)
    - Europe; Far East, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Europe, 1962-1969 (Box 5, Folder 32-40)
    - Around the World, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Japan; Hong Kong; Taiwan, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 42-43)
    - Europe, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 44-45)
    - Japan, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Europe, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Seattle, Washington; Japan, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Europe, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Japan, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - China, Art and Archaeology Delegation, Travel Diaries, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - China, Art and Archaeology Delegation, Travel Diary, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - China, Art and Archaeology Delegation, Itineraries, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - China, Art and Archaeology Delegation, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 4-6)
    - China, Art and Archaeology Delegation, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Europe, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Ireland, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Japan, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Europe, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Japan, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - France; Belgium; England, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
    - Europe, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Japan; United States, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - French Polynesia; Australia; Japan; France; England, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - England; France; Switzerland; Ireland, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - England; France, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Hong Kong; Japan, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - England; Scotland, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Japan; Hong Kong; Taiwan, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Germany; England; France, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Japan, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 24-25)
    - Switzerland; Germany; Austria; Netherlands; Denmark; England, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Japan, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 27-31)
    - England, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - England; Ireland, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - England; Japan, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - China; Japan, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - General, 1988-1994; 5.2
    - Japan, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Europe, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
    - China, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Japan; China; Hong Kong, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Europe, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Japan; China; Hong Kong, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
    - Europe, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Japan; Hong Kong, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
- Committees and Organizations Files, 1971-1997; Series 6; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 7-8
  This series consists of records relating to Lee's affiliation with committees and organizations including the Arts and Artifacts Indemnity Program, the Internal Revenue Service Advisory Panel, and the National Council on the Arts. Files may include photographs of works of art, minutes, project proposals, correspondence, drafts of writings, and printed material.
  - Ackland Art Museum, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - American Assembly, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 14-18)
  - Amon Carter Museum, 1991-1996 (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
  - Arts and Artifacts Indemnity Program, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Asia Society, 1993-1997 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Asian Cultural Council, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1990-1996 (Box 7)
  - Committee on the Humanities, 1978-1981 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Foundation for Art Education, 1976-1980 (Box 7, Folder 26-28)
  - Freer Gallery of Art, 1993-1996 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Internal Revenue Service Advisory Panel, 1967-1994 (Box 8, Folder 3-5)
  - Japan Society, 1989-1996 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - National Council on the Arts, 1971-1975 (Box 8, Folder 7-12)
- Consulting Files, 1960-1993; Series 7; 1.1 Linear feet Boxes 8-9
  Consulting files contain material regarding Lee's consulting work with the John D. Rockefeller III Collection, the Permanent Public Areas Advisory Committee of Cleveland, Ohio, and others. Files may contain correspondence, printed material, reports, and legal documents including contracts.
  - John D. Rockefeller III, Collection Recommendations, 1960-1983 (Box 8, Folder 13-19)
  - John D. Rockefeller III, Asian Art Selections Exhibition, 1969-1975 (Box 8, Folder 20-21)
  - John D. Rockefeller III, Bequests, 1976-1979 (Box 8, Folder 22-23)
  - Min Chiu Society, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Marcus, Margaret, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Permanent Public Areas Advisory Committee, Cleveland State University, Frank J. Lausche Building, 1977-1981 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Permanent Public Areas Advisory Committee, Jesse Owens Memorial Sculpture, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Permanent Public Areas Advisory Committee, Justice Center, 1972-1974 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Permanent Public Areas Advisory Committee, Justice Center, Grants and Applications, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Permanent Public Areas Advisory Committee, Justice Center, Art Advisory Committee, 1974-1978 (Box 9, Folder 7-9)
  - Permanent Public Areas Advisory Committee, Justice Center, Dedication Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Permanent Public Areas Advisory Committee, Justice Center, Local and Regional Competitions, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
  - Permanent Public Areas Advisory Committee, Justice Center, Sculptures, 1976-1981 (Box 9, Folder 13-16)
  - Permanent Public Areas Advisory Committee, Justice Center, Photographs, 1971-1977 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Permanent Public Areas Advisory Committee, Medical Mutual Building, 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Permanent Public Areas Advisory Committee, Sohio Office Building, 1977-1982 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Pritzker Collection, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Teaching Files, 1963-1977; Series 8; 0.1 Linear feet Box 9
  Teaching files consist of records from classes taught by Lee at Case Western Reserve University and Harvard University.
  - Case Western Reserve University, Far Eastern Art History, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Case Western Reserve University, Later Chinese Painting, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Case Western Reserve University, Chinese Ceramics, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Case Western Reserve University, Japanese Painting, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Case Western Reserve University, Far Eastern Art History, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Harvard University, Summer Session, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Personal Business Records, 1958-1995; Series 9; 0.3 Linear feet Box 9
  This series consists of records relating to Lee's personal art collection, estate records, and an oral history agreement and transcript.
  - Personal Art Collection, Lists and Invoices, 1969-1973 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Personal Art Collection, Rights and Permissions, 1967-1981 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Personal Art Collection, Puchases, 1958-1982 (Box 9, Folder 29-31)
  - Personal Art Collection, Loans, 1967-1981 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Personal Art Collection, Gifts and Donations, 1958-1980 (Box 9, Folder 33-34)
  - Will and Estate, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Oral History Agreement and Transcript, 1992-1995 (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Printed Material, 1962-1987; Series 10; 0.9 Linear feet Boxes 10-11
  Printed materials include clippings, programs from various events, and museum bulletins.
  - Clippings, 1962-1987 (Box 10, Folder 1-6)
  - Programs, 1960s-1980s (Box 10, Folder 7-11)
  - Museum Bulletins, 1970s-1980 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Oversized Clippings and Poster, 1960s (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Photographs, circa 1952-1993; Series 11; 0.2 Linear feet Boxes 10-11
  Photographs are of Sherman Lee and of Works of Art.
  - of Sherman Lee, circa 1960-1993 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Works of Art, Under Consideration at Cleveland Museum of Art, circa 1952-1983 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Works of Art, 1960s-1970s (Box 10, Folder 15-25)
  - Oversized Photos of Works of Art, circa 1960 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Artwork, circa 1960s; Series 12; 1 Folders Box 10
  Artwork consists of a pencil drawing by an unidentified artist.
  - Portrait of a Woman, Pencil, Unidentified, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 26)